Guide to The Billie Jean King Collection 1901-2019 (bulk, 1940-2019) MS 3147
New-York Historical Society
- Series IV. Speeches, 2002-2019; 2 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
  - Radcliffe Institute for Advanced Study, 2002 June 7 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 16)
    Contains typed remarks for the 2002 Radcliffe Medal ceremony. Subjects of remarks include BJK's personal and career history, facing discrimination, activism, and the importance of sport.
  - Celebration of Women in Sports at Cedar Crest College, 2002 October 24 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 17)
    Contains typed speech with handwritten edits, event memos, and schedule for the day's events. Topics of BJK's remarks include the Battle of the Sexes, Women's Sports Foundation, and encouraging student activism.
  - Linkage, Inc. Women in Leadership conference, 2003 February 10 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 18)
    Contains typed remarks with handwritten notes. Topics of remarks include taking responsibility for social change, the Battle of the Sexes match, and the Women's Tennis Association.
  - Office Depot Success Strategies for Businesswomen, 2003 February 24 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 19)
    Includes typed speech with many handwritten notes, edits, and additions. Topics include leadership, success, advocating for equality and progress, and the function of sport in society.
  - NACWAA [National Association of Collegiate Women Athletics Administrators], 2003 March 10 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 20)
    Contains typed remarks. Topics include social change and equality in sports, Title IX, and the Women's Sports Foundation.
  - Life and Style Series, 2003 May 19 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 21)
    Typed remarks with handwritten edits. Topics include personal challenges faced by BJK throughout her life and career, recognizing injustice, advocacy, and the state of women's sports.
  - JPMorgan Chase Pride, 2003 June 18 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 22)
    Contains typed notes for remarks with many handwritten additions and edits. Topics of remarks include JP Morgan Chase's sponsorship of various tennis events, homophobia experienced by LGBTQ youth, LGBTQ inclusion in the workplace, and the JP Morgan Chase Pride Group tenets.
  - US Open Court of Champions, 2003 August (Offsite-box 21, Folder 23)
    Contains handwritten speech. Topics include childhood experiences with tennis, USTA leadership, and equality in earnings for women's tennis.
  - National Women's Party, 2004 May 4 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 24)
    Contains materials from The Alice Award ceremony of the National Women's Party honoring BJK, including typed and handwritten remarks and event program. Topics of remarks include gender discrimination, social change, activism, Title IX, and the Women's Sports Foundation.
  - Lehman Brothers, 2004 June 16 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 25)
    Contains material from a Lehman Brothers Gay & Lesbian Network event, including itinerary, background information on Lehman Brothers and past events, and BJK's typed remarks. Topics of BJK's remarks include personal history, homophobia experienced by LGBTQ youth, and the Women's Sports Foundation.
  - Out and Equal Workplace Summit, 2004 October 1 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 26)
    Contains typed and handwritten notes for BJK's remarks. Topics include BJK's personal experiences throughout her tennis career, particularly the Battle of the Sexes, being outed and losing endorsements, and struggles and work towards economic equality for women's tennis, as well as the importance of LGBTQ visibility in the workplace.
  - Olivia women's leadership summit, 2005 April 4 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 27)
    Contains materials from the Olivia women's leadership summit and cruise, including program, itinerary, correspondence, terms of agreement, and BJK's typed and handwritten notes for her speech. Topics of remarks include leadership, legacy, personal challenges and lessons through life and career, and the importance of visibility for women in power and for the LGBTQ community.
  - International Tennis Hall of Fame Salute to Tony Trabert, 2005 May 3 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 28)
    Contains program and BJK's typed and handwritten remarks honoring tennis champion Tony Trabert.
  - Credit Suisse First Boston, 2005 June 9 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 29)
    Contains articles and BJK's remarks from Pride month speaking engagement at Credit Suisse First Boston. Topics of remarks include BJK's personal history, the importance of LGBTQ visibility, and addressing discrimination in the workplace.
  - Novo Nordisk Awards, 2005 July 5 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 30)
    Contains BJK's typed remarks for the Novo Nordisk Awards, a BJK World TeamTennis Charities event created with Diane Donnelly Stone and Tracey Donnelly Maltby in 1988 honoring tennis players with diabetes age 14-21. Remarks introduce two recipients of the awarded scholarships.
  - Women's Networking Night, 2005 July 6 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 31)
    Contains materials from Women's Networking Night with World TeamTennis and Olivia, including the event agenda and printed web articles.
  - Advanta Small Business Summit, 2005 July 13 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 32)
    Contains agenda, printed email correspondence, and BJK's remarks for panel. Topics of remarks include the history of World TeamTennis and business lessons learned from WTT operations.
  - CityParks Foundation dinner, 2005 August 30 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 33)
    Contains correspondence and BJK's typed remarks with handwritten notes. Remarks include introduction about the importance of parks tennis programs and the presentation of community service award to Mary Carillo.
  - WTA Partners for Success, 2005 September 1 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 34)
    Contains handwritten schedule, printed materials from the Women's Tennis Association Partners for Success mentor program filming and event.
  - World TeamTennis 30th Reunion, 2005 September 6 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 35)
    Contains typed notes with handwritten additions for BJK's remarks about experiences as a founder and player with World TeamTennis at the WTT 30th Reunion Party.
  - Cal State LA, 2005 September 24 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 36)
    Contains materials from BJK and Friends, Presenting The Joe Shapiro Award held at the Cal State LA Tennis Complex, including printed email correspondence and the schedule of events with handwritten notes.
  - Women's Sports Foundation dinner, 2005 October 12 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 37)
    Contains printed material, invitation, and handwritten notes for introductions of the recipients of awards from the Women's Sports Foundation's Annual Salute to Women in Sports Awards Dinner and Auction.
  - Executive Forum on Sports and Social Responsibility, 2005 October 19 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 38)
    Contains conference program, typed itinerary, and typed interview questions for BJK with handwritten notes.
  - California Governor's Conference on Women & Families, 2005 October 27 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 39)
    Contains typed questions and suggested topics for BJK on Architects of Change panel.
  - Women's Event 8, 2005 October 29 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 40)
    Contains materials from The Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual & Transgender Community Center's Women's Event 8, including newsletter, handwritten schedule of events, and typed remarks for BJK's introduction of honoree Judy Dlugacz, president and founder of Olivia Cruises and Resorts.
  - Westchester Fund for Women and Girls, 2005 November 4 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 41)
    Contains program, background information, and BJK's typed remarks with handwritten edits for the Westchester Fund for Women and Girls 10th Anniversary Breakfast. Topics of remarks include creating a legacy, personal and professional milestones throughout BJK's life, and using personal strengths to make a difference.
  - March of Dimes luncheon, 2005 November 30 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 42)
    Contains materials including typed and printed webpage schedules of events and BJK's typed notes for introducing U.S. women's soccer players at Sportswomen of the Year.
  - Smart Talk for Women, 2006 February 27 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 44)
    Contains event program and BJK's typed notes with handwritten additions. Topics of remarks include legacy, milestones in life and career, mentorship, and advocacy for equality.
  - Althea Gibson video tribute, 2006 April (Offsite-box 21, Folder 45)
    Contains BJK's typed remarks for appearing in a video played at the tribute for the 50th Anniversary of Althea Gibson's Grand Slam wins and reception for Angela Buxton. Remarks include BJK's recollections of Gibson and her influence.
  - Gene Scott Service, 2006 April 1 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 46)
    Contains newspaper clippings and BJK's typed remarks for tennis player and journalist Gene Scott's memorial service.
  - The Billies, 2006 April 20 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 47)
    Contains event files, programs, seating arrangements, and schedule of events for the Women's Sports Foundation's Billie Awards.
  - Jewish Sports Hall of Fame, 2006 April 30 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 48)
    Contains printed material from The Jewish Sports Hall of Fame and typed remarks of Ilana Kloss speaking on her experiences as a Jewish athlete.
  - Lambda Legal Liberty Awards, 2006 May 8 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 49)
    Contains printed material and BJK's typed remarks with handwritten edits. Topics of remarks include Lambda's work, BJK's experience after being outed, and the importance of visibility.
  - Starkey Hearing Foundation, 2006 June 17 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 50)
    Contains printed materials, gala schedule with handwritten notes.
  - Dr. Dorothy Gulbenkian Blaney memorial service, 2006 July 20 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 51)
    Contains typed BJK remarks for the memorial service for Dr. Dorothy Blaney, president of Cedar Crest College and member and past chairman of the Women's Sports Foundation.
  - USTA naming ceremony, 2006 August 28 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 52)
    Contains schedule, ticket assignments, printed email correspondence, and BJK's typed remarks for the naming ceremony of the BJK National Tennis Center. Topics of BJK's remarks include many thanks, turning points in her career, the importance of public parks, and bringing inspiration to others.
  - PepsiCo Diversity Week, 2006 September 12 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 1)
    Contains background documents on PepsiCo diversity week initiatives and typed remarks with handwritten comments for BJK's remarks. Topics of remarks include PepsiCo's diversity efforts, employee networking and leadership, personal life and career milestones, and progress towards inclusion in the workplace.
  - San Francisco GLBT Historical Society, 2006 September 28 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 2)
    Contains gala program and BJK's typed and handwritten notes for remarks. Topics of remarks include the work of the GLBT Historical Society, documenting history, and the importance of legacy.
  - Cal State LA, 2006 September 30 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 3)
    Contains program and BJK's typed remarks with handwritten notes from the 2006 BJK and Friends Presenting the Joe Shapiro Award event at Cal State LA. Remarks comprised of the introduction of CSULA student-athletes and coaches.
  - Enduring Vision, 2006 October 3 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 4)
    Contains printed email correspondence and schedule and BJK's typed notes for brief remarks upon accepting an award presented to BJK and Ilana Kloss at the Elton John AIDS Foundation Enduring Vision gala.
  - Merrill Lynch, 2006 October 5 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 5)
    Contains printed itinerary and presenter slide presentation for "Achieving Life: An Intimate Conversation with Billie Jean King" Merrill Lynch event.
  - Human Rights Campaign, 2006 October 7 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 6)
    Contains material from the tenth annual Human Rights Campaign National Dinner, at which BJK was presented with the Sports Legend & Social Activist HRC National Equality Award. Materials include event program, printed itinerary, and BJK's typed acceptance remarks with many handwritten additions and edits.
  - Women's World Awards, 2006 October 14 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 7)
    Contains event program, printed schedule, and BJK's typed remarks on women's empowerment from the Women's World Awards.
  - BJK International Women's Sports Center, 2006 October 17 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 8)
    Contains schedule and typed remarks of BJK and Ilana Kloss for ribbon-cutting ceremony and press conference of the BJK International Women's Sports Center.
  - USTA Middle States Hall of Fame dinner, 2006 October 20 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 9)
    Contains printed material and photocopies of emails, event itinerary, and list of attendees.
  - Merrill Lynch diversity and inclusion conference, 2006 October 23 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 10)
    Contains BJK's typed remarks with handwritten notes. Topics of remarks include personal challenges and milestones, progress towards LGBTQ inclusion in the workplace, and the importance of visibility.
  - Merrill Lynch, 2006 October 26 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 11)
    Contains typed comments for Paula Polioto's presentation with BJK and an issue of Merrill Lynch Advisor with article on BJK.
  - Glamour Women of the Year Awards, 2006 October 30 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 12)
    Contains materials from the 17th Annual Glamour Women of the Year Awards, including program, invitations, correspondence, and BJK's typed remarks with handwritten additions. Topics of remarks include social responsibility and a call to action to work towards gender equality.
  - Ham Richardson service, 2006 November 15 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 13)
    Contains program and BJK's typed remarks for the memorial service for tennis player Hamilton Richardson.
  - March of Dimes sports luncheon, 2006 November 29 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 14)
    Contains schedule, program, and BJK's typed remarks for presenting the March of Dimes 2006 Corporate Leadership Award to Ross Greenburg, president of HBO Sports.
  - Northeastern University Sport in Society, 2006 December 4 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 15)
    Contains correspondence, program, and BJK's typed remarks with handwritten additions. Topics of remarks include the work of the Center for the Study of Sport in Society, the Women's Sports Foundation, and the importance of sport.
  - California Hall of Fame induction, 2006 December 6 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 16)
    Contains invitations, inductee information sheets with itinerary, and BJK bio for California Hall of Fame induction ceremony.
  - Visionary Innovator Caregiver presentation, circa 2007 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 17)
    Contains printed color slides presentation on BJK's personal biography, achievements, and speaking skills aimed towards brands and companies interested in partnering with or hiring BJK for an event.
  - Omega Institute, 2007 January 13 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 18)
    Contains event programs and BJK's typed remarks with handwritten edits for the Omega Institute's Being Ageless event. Topics of remarks include the concept of agelessness, transitioning throughout different life stages, milestones in professional and personal life, and a call to action and defining one's legacy.
  - HSBC, 2007 January 19 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 19)
    Contains BJK's typed remarks with handwritten edits for the HSBC Consumer Lending Conference. Topics of remarks include leadership, ownership, BJK career milestones, and teamwork.
  - Red Dress Heart Truth, 2007 February 2 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 20)
    Contains printed material and printed webpage articles related to Red Dress Heart Truth Event, including runway show, that BJK participated in.
  - NEA [National Education Association] Foundation, 2007 February 8 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 21)
    Contains event program and BJK's printed remarks with handwritten edits for the NEA Foundation Dinner and her acceptance of the NEA Foundation Award for Outstanding Service to Public Education. Topics of remarks include the importance of educators, teachers throughout BJK's childhood, and Title IX.
  - Oprah & Friends Radio Show, 2007 February 14 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 22)
    Contains email and typed notes for BJK interview with Gayle King about eco-sports initiative GreenSlam.
  - Miracle Corners of the World, 2007 March 5 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 23)
    Contains printed material from Miracle Corners of the World and letter to BJK and Ilana Kloss with invitation to accept the MCW Public-Private Partnership Award at the 2006 Gala Dinner.
  - PepsiCo Multicultural Inclusion Summit, 2007 March 27 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 24)
    Contains agenda and BJK's typed remarks with handwritten edits. Topics of remarks include awareness, focus and commitment, and a call to action to drive change.
  - Cleveland Title IX events, 2007 March 29-31 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 25)
    Contains BJK's typed remarks for various events in Cleveland, including at the Women's Basketball Coaches Association Meeting of Assistant Coaches, at the Title IX Hoopla, and for media appearances at WKYC-TV3 Good Company Live Talk Show. Topic of all remarks is Title IX. Also contains event programs.
  - The Billies, 2007 April 11 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 26)
    Contains email, event program, and mailings for The Billie Awards.
  - White House Project EPIC Awards, 2007 April 18 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 27)
    Contains event program and BJK's typed remarks with handwritten edits. Topics of remarks include gender equality and a call to vote.
  - Tribeca Film Festival, 2007 April 24 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 28)
    Contains printed email correspondence and typed notes for BJK's remarks at the opening night for Tribeca Film Festival. Topics of remarks include BJK's role as ambassador for the the Tribeca/ESPN Sports Film Festival.
  - Stanford Title IX conference, 2007 April 29-30 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 29)
    Contains printed emails, Title IX report, and BJK's handwritten notecards for remarks on Title IX.
  - New England Institute of Technology, 2007 May 6 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 30)
    Contains Commencement program, BJK's typed Commencement Speech for New England Institute of Technology graduation. Topics of remarks include BJK's personal milestones, overcoming obstacles, accepting responsibility, believing in yourself, and a call to action to drive change.
  - Indianapolis Motor Speedway, 2007 May 7-11 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 31)
    Contains itinerary and printed email correspondence related to BJK's role as honorary starter for race.
  - Merrill Lynch, 2007 May 10 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 32)
    Contains itinerary, list of attendees for Achieving Life: An Evening with BJK event.
  - Phoenix Women's Sports Association Dinner, 2007 May 19 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 33)
    Contains BJK's typed remarks with handwritten additions. Topics of remarks include inspiration, accepting responsibility, following your passions, and giving back.
  - Women for Hillary town hall breakfast, 2007 June 4 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 34)
    Contains BJK's typed remarks with handwritten edits. BJK's remarks describe her commitment to HRC and their shared values and beliefs.
  - Hillary Clinton Club 44, 2007 June 6 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 35)
    Contains printed event information, printed script, and BJK's handwritten notecards for remarks on HRC.
  - Center on Halsted, 2007 June 8 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 36)
    Contains BJK's typed remarks for Center on Halsted Gala Dinner and dedication of the BJK Recreational Hall. Topics of remarks include the work of Center on Halsted and the Chicago community.
  - Goldman Sachs, 2007 June 21 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 37)
    Contains BJK's typed keynote remarks, booking and appearance forms for Goldman Sachs Diversity Event. Topics of remarks include commitment to diversity and inclusion, visible leadership, legacy, milestones in BJK's life and career, and the Women's Sports Foundation.
  - Hypertension Education Foundation, 2007 June 11-12 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 38)
    Contains BJK's itinerary for media training and satellite media tour schedule.
  - UBS diversity event, 2007 June 13 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 39)
    Contains BJK's typed remarks for keynote "Creating a Legacy." Topics of remarks include diversity and inclusion initiatives at UBS, visible leadership, legacy, personal and professional milestones in BJK's life, and progress and challenges in seeking equality in the workplace.
  - World TeamTennis Women's Networking Night, 2007 July 12 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 40)
    Contains event flier and BJK's typed remarks for Women's Networking Night in Delaware. Topics of remarks include history of World TeamTennis, the Women's Sports Foundation, and legacy.
  - Lords and Commons Tennis Club, 2007 July 3 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 41)
    Contains event itinerary and typed list of potential interview questions for BJK.
  - California Museum for History, 2007 July 29 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 42)
    Contains BJK's typed script for taping for the California Museum for History. BJK's script focuses on the California Hall of Fame, of which BJK is an inaugural inductee.
  - Foudy Sports Leadership Academy, 2007 July 30 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 43)
    Contains BJK's typed notes for remarks with handwritten edits. Topics of remarks include Julie Foudy's career, leadership, and the Leadership Academy.
  - Women's Leadership Exchange, 2007 August 14 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 44)
    Contains correspondence and BJK's typed remarks upon accepting the Vanguard Award at the Women's Leadership Exchange. Topics of remarks include BJK's experience as a businesswoman and entrepreneur, the Original 9 and birth of women's professional tennis, and the Women's Tennis Association.
  - World TeamTennis Rec Finals, 2007 August 17 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 45)
    Contains BJK's handwritten notes for remarks, including comments on her story, equality, World TeamTennis, and creating opportunity.
  - Harlem Junior Tennis and Education Program, 2007 August 23 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 46)
    Contains printed fact sheets and BJK's handwritten notes for remarks. Topics of remarks include the history of the Harlem Junior Tennis and Education Program, importance of sports for children, and educational support initiative.
  - JPMorgan Asset Management, 2007 August 27 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 47)
    Contains BJK's typed remarks for JPMorgan Asset Management event at the US Open. Remarks include thanks to JPMorgan for support and sponsorship of the US Open, history of the US Open, and comments on the upcoming matches.
  - CityParks Tennis, 2007 August 28 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 48)
    Contains BJK's typed remarks welcoming attendees to CityParks Tennis Benefit and thanking those involved.
  - UBS, 2007 September 4 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 49)
    Contains service agreement between UBS and BJK Enterprises, Inc. for appearance and photographs.
  - Goldman Sachs, 2007 September 6 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 50)
    Contains printed discussion topics for Leadership Panel: A New Perspective at the 3rd Annual Capital Markets Roundtable.
  - International Women's Forum Gala, 2007 September 12 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 51)
    Contains event program and BJK's typed remarks with handwritten edits for The International Women's Forum Gala's presentation of the Hall of Fame Award. Topics of remarks include leadership, giving back, the Women's Sports Foundation, and mentorship.
  - NRPA [National Recreation and Parks Administration] Congress, 2007 September 26 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 52)
    Contains typed prepared questions for Mary Joe Fernandez and BJK.
  - Fortune Most Powerful Women, 2007 October 1-3 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 53)
    Contains printed email correspondence, service agreement, list of attendees, and event itinerary.
  - Cal State LA, 2007 October 6 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 54)